<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">AndroidHealth</string>
    <string name="symptoms">Many symptoms can indicate depression. You may have no interest in things you used to enjoy, and feel guilty, sad, or upset most of the time, for many days. Some sadness is normal in everyone’s life, but if yours is keeping you from doing what you enjoy, it may be a sign of depression.</string>
    <string name="not_enjoying">If you used to love to go on walks, garden or watch TV with your family and those activities no longer make you happy and have not made you happy for a long time, you may be depressed.</string>
    <string name="thinking_bad">If you spend a lot of your time thinking you have somehow failed the people around you, or that you are worthless, these may be symptoms of depression.</string>
    <string name="thinking_hurting">If you have thoughts about hurting yourself, those thoughts may be because of depression, which is treatable. Doctors can help you feel good again.</string>
    <string name="trouble_sleeping">Some people need less sleep than others – and some people are happier in the morning than others. But if you are feeling extra tired and have been sleeping more or less than you usually do, this might be a sign of a mental health concern. The same goes for your appetite – some people eat more than others, but if you are getting hungry throughout the day (or are barely eating at all) this could also be a symptom.</string>
    <string name="difficulty_focusing">It can also be frustrating if you have trouble focusing or getting things done. If you can’t focus on the activities you normally enjoy – it can be a sign of depression. Sometimes you may feel you are moving in slow motion and sometimes you may feel you have too much energy and need to go at 110 mph. Either change in your usual mood could be something your doctor can help you with.</string>
    <string name="no_single_symptom">No single symptom proves you have depression. Doctors must look at all your symptoms together and talk to you to figure out if you need treatment.</string>
    <string name="diagnosis">Unfortunately there are no biological tests that can prove whether or not you have depression.  There are many types of depression, and depression can often happen at the same time of another illness.  Only a doctor can diagnose depression.</string>
    <string name="diagnosis_doctor">Your doctor will need to make sure other illnesses aren’t causing your depression. He or she will ask you how you feel, and may have you fill out a survey about your moods, how long your different feelings have lasted, any other changes in your life, and physical symptoms. These questions will help the doctor identify whether you have depression or another illness, and if you have depression, what kind of depression you might have.</string>
    <string name="causes">There is no one cause of depression. Different people get depressed for very different reasons. Some causes of depression may include personal problems, serious illnesses, conflict with others, and changes in your body.</string>
    <string name="life_events">Life events such as getting divorced, moving, or retiring can be part of causing depression. Even positive life events, such as getting married, having a baby or starting a new job can lead to depression.</string>
    <string name="conflict">Conflict with friends or family, as well as other problems, like major illnesses, any kind of abuse, stress, loss of a loved one, or feelings of loneliness can also lead to depression.</string>
    <string name="medications_cause">Some medications can also cause depression. You may want to check with your doctor if you think a medication you are taking might be making you depressed (for example, if the depression started after you started a new medication).</string>
    <string name="family_history">If your family has a history of depression, this increases your likelihood of becoming depressed. But people who do not have a family history of depression can also become depressed.</string>
    <string name="hormones">Women are twice as likely to experience depression as men. This may be due to hormones, or may be due to life events or social experiences that are unique to women. For instance, many women become depressed briefly after giving birth. This is known as the &quot;baby blues.&quot; For some women, however, this depression may last for much longer, and is called postpartum depression.</string>
    <string name="depression_no_fault">If you are depressed, it is not your fault. No one knows exactly what causes depression, and depression is different in everyone. Almost one fifth of all women in the United States, and over one tenth of all men become depressed at some point in their lives.</string>
    <string name="ssris">SSRIs work by increasing the amount of serotonin in your cells. Serotonin is a chemical in your brain that is known to cause feelings of happiness. Common SSRIs are the drugs Prozac, Zoloft, and Celexa.</string>
    <string name="snris">SNRIs are another kind of antidepressant that, like SSRIs, increase the amount of serotonin in your cells. However, they also increase another chemical called norepinephrine in your cells.</string>
    <string name="other_meds">Other, less common drugs to treat depression include Tricyclics (such as Elavil and Norpramin) and monoamine oxidase inhibitors (MAOIs), such as Nardil and Parnate. These drugs are less commonly used because they may have more side effects than SSRIs and SNRIs.</string>
    <string name="therapy">Medication is not the only way to help depression. Therapy, or talking to a trained professional, can be as helpful if not more helpful for people with depression. Most studies show that combining medication with talk therapy is the most effective. Ask your doctor for referrals to therapists in the area. Many therapists provide free or reduced services.</string>
    <string name="continue_meds">You should continue taking the drug your doctor gives you for as long as he/she tells you to, even if you start to feel better! This is very important, because if you stop before you are supposed to, your symptoms will likely come back. Often people have to stop taking their antidepressants gradually, to let their body adjust.</string>
    <string formatted="false" name="treatment">Antidepressants are a medication you can take in a pill. They are the most common treatment for depression.</string>
</resources>
